# Craig M. Sirota

♦ (908) 894-8339 ♦ CraigMSirota@gmail.com ♦ 730 N 16th Street, Unit 3, Philadelphia, PA 19130 ♦ http://www.linkedin.com/in/CraigMSirota ♦

# **Technical Skills & Languages**

Python, Java, Javascript, Ruby, Rails, React, Flask, C, C++, HTML, CSS, SQL, CCL, XML, Maven, NPM, Git, Jira, Accessibility (WCAG 2.1), Jenkins, Docker, Android Studio, AWS EC2, Linux, Windows, MacOS

## **PROJECTS**

#### Revenue Cycle Management - Oracle Corporation - (Oct. 2020-Present)

An application designed to simplify the registration, scheduling, and billing of patients at medical facilities or within medical networks

#### Add Appointment Plus Accessibility Uplift - React/Java - (April 2022-Present)

 Led the accessibility uplift of a complex workflow to meet the WCAG 2.1 standard, ensuring compliance and usability for users with disabilities.

## Screen Reader Not Reading From Embedded Browser Investigation - (Oct. 2022-Jan. 2023)

• Investigated and resolved an issue with screen reader accessibility in the Add Appointment Plus project, documented findings, and recommended solutions to UX and regulatory personnel.

# **Location Based Scheduling - CCL - (April 2022-May 2022)**

• Resolved a bug in the scheduling system that caused appointments to be scheduled for the wrong date in certain timezones, improving scheduling accuracy and user experience.

#### Location Description Enter Information - Java/SQL - (Jan. 2022-March 2022)

 Added a new feature that allows system administrators to select how users view location information, enhancing customization and user experience.

#### Kiosk Profiles Admin Build Tool Uplift - React/Ruby on Rails - (July 2021-Dec. 2021)

 Upgraded a Rails-based UI to a React-based UI using a Rails Engine, improving performance and usability for administrators.

# Scheduling Security Server - C++ - (March 2021-June 2021)

 Developed a new feature for the security server that allows users to have "all" as a permission, reducing database size and increasing efficiency.

# Manual Scheduling Uplift - React - (Oct. 2020-March 2021)

 Upgraded an existing scheduling feature from Java to React, allowing users to drag and drop appointments onto a schedule, improving usability and efficiency.

# Automated Live Virtual Assistant Network (A.L.V.A.N.) - Flask/React - Personal Project - (Feb. 2020-Present)

- A custom home automation/virtual assistant network similar to a Google Home or Amazon Alexa, utilizing a custom linear regression machine learning algorithm to determine the proper response to user queries.
- o Required a modular design to make new features work seamlessly in a "plug and play" style
- o Currently the backend is deployed on an AWS EC2 instance, frontend on github pages

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Software Engineer:**

#### Oracle Corporation (formerly Cerner Corporation) - (July 2020-Present)

- Worked with stakeholders to produce software to satisfy their needs while putting out quality, tested code in a timely manner
- Participated in code reviews, making sure everything put out by the team was up to the company's high standard

# **Cofounder/Technical Producer/Team Manager:**

## College Band Radio - (June 2020-Dec 2022)

- o Cofounder of a podcast discussing the college marching band world.
- Managed the logistics and scheduling of planning and recording, and oversaw the editing process to make sure episodes were ready to be released on time, up to our standards.

#### **AWARDS**

## RCM (Revenue Cycle Management) Champion Award - Q2 2022

o Recognition of outstanding contribution to the success of Cerner Revenue Cycle

## **EDUCATION**

Rutgers University - New Brunswick, NJ - B.S. Computer Science - 2020